#### Contact

lauren.newman7@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/laurennewman-99565a153 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Computer Literacy
Team Management
Critical Thinking

# Lauren Newman

Critical Care at Christ Medical Center House Supervisor at MacNeal Hospital Telemetry/Trach RN BSN CMSRN

Chicago, Illinois

### Summary

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Team Leader, Mac Neal Hospital, Berwyn IL, December 2016-Present

Permanent Charge Nurse that includes working closely with the Hospital House Supervisor, assigning admissions, and serving as an educational resource to staff nurses.

Focuses on unit specific initiatives to improve patient experience and staff retention.

Precepts new graduate nurses to the unit.

Currently training for "PRN House Supervisor".

Telemetry Nurse, Mac Neal Hospital, Berwyn IL, April 2015-Present Monitors continuous telemetry recording and cares for tracheostomy and ventilator patients.

Cares for patients with a wide range of complicated medical histories and acute diagnoses such as cardiac chest pain in which prepping the patient for stress tests and the catheterization lab are of priority, gastrointestinal hemorrhaging, and renal insufficiency.

Recognizes changes in patient condition and acts appropriately.

Assists in rapid responses and code blues.

Assesses plans, performs, and evaluates treatments for individualized care plans.

Provides education regarding medications and treatments.

Recognized on "The Pulse" for a "Good Catch" in October of 2015.

Nomination for Nurse Excellence Award in 2015 and 2016.

Patient Care Technician, Mac Neal Hospital, Berwyn IL, June 2013-April 2015

Performed vital signs, blood draws, electrocardiograms, and patient care such as bathing, oral care, and linen changes.

Floated and experience in many units of the hospital such as motherbaby, pediatrics, telemetry, behavioral health, orthopedic, and neurological units.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Licensed Professional Registered Nurse 2015 to Present CPR and ACLS re-certified as of 2017

Member of Team Leader Committee

Member Clinical Practice Council and Shared Governance.

Currently studying for CMSRN certification.

## Experience

MacNeal Hospital

5 years 3 months

House Supervisor

October 2017 - Present (2 years 9 months)

MacNeal Hospital

**PRN** 

Team Lead

January 2017 - Present (3 years 6 months)

Telemetry

Registered Nurse

April 2015 - Present (5 years 3 months)

### Education

Northern Illinois University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Registered Nursing/Registered

Nurse · (2011 - 2014)

**Bradley University** 

Master of Science in Nursing, Family Practice Nurse/Nursing · (2018 - 2021)